Contact

jcb914@charter.net

www.linkedin.com/in/jcb914 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Patient Safety
Hospitals
Healthcare Management

Joan Becker, RN

Senior Patient Experience Advisor at SSM Health

Greater St. Louis Area

Summary

I am a RN with over 30 years of experience. I have more than 25 years experience in management and leadership positions where I had consistent success in building highly engaged teams. Currently I am working as a Senior Patient Experience Advisor at SSM Healthcare. I believe excellent patient care starts at the top with strong and consistent leadership.

Experience

SSM Health St. Louis
Senior Patient Experience Advisor
October 2018 - Present (1 year 10 months)
Greater St. Louis Area

SSM Health

Senior Patient Experience Advisor October 2018 - Present (1 year 10 months)

Barnes Jewish Hosptial
Patient Experience Partner
October 2011 - Present (8 years 10 months)

Coach and mentor BJH leaders and team members along with physicians in establishing and hardwiring the ICARE core values of the organization.

Work collaboratively with senior leadership at BJH to provide coaching, training, and mentoring to front line managers and team members to improve employee engagement and the patient experience.

Prepare and present oral intitiatives to address service excellence and leadership development.

Collect, analyze and interprets data as it relates to the patient experience and ICARE initiatives.

Design and deploy coaching/learning initiatives on performance requirements and monitor progress.

Barnes-Jewish Hospital RN, Clinical Nurse Manager August 2007 - October 2011 (4 years 3 months)

Managed several surgical units at BJH. Frequently called to manage units that were struggling with performance and engagement issues. Successful at building a highly functional team and improving employee engagement and patient satisfactions scores.

Belleville Memorial Hospital
Clinical Nurse Manager- Telemetry
July 2002 - August 2007 (5 years 2 months)

Managed business and clinical operations of 36 bed telemetry unit.

Education

Webster University

Master of Business Administration (MBA), Health Services

Management · (1998)

University of Missouri - St. Louis
BSN, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (1987 - 1991)

Barnes Hospital School of Nursing Diploma in Nursing (1983 - 1986)